<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zlog - the zigius blog</title><link>https://zigius.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on zlog - the zigius blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 19:42:36 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zigius.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitor Athena Datalake Tables</title><link>https://zigius.github.io/posts/monitor-athena-datalake-tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 19:42:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://zigius.github.io/posts/monitor-athena-datalake-tables/</guid><description>Today we are going to talk about monitoring our datalake tables.
At my company we have a datalake containing more than 3PB of data. The raw data is saved as compressed parquet files in S3. We query our datalake using athena. We needed a way to monitor our data to be able to quickly detect issues in our data pipeline.
We decided we want to be able to monitor various scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Embedding an image in a markdown file using google api and luasnip</title><link>https://zigius.github.io/posts/creating-drive-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 02:58:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://zigius.github.io/posts/creating-drive-plugin/</guid><description>Im currently working on building my second brain. I use neovim for everything I can. Seems like a no brainer to also try and use neovim as my notetaking app. A second brain consists of notes, images, videos, and much more. This post will focus on my workflow for adding images to markdown files.
Storing images I store my notes in a github repo, and of course also locally on my laptop and phone.</description></item><item><title>The story of the content-length header</title><link>https://zigius.github.io/posts/nodejs_content_length_timeout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 15:59:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://zigius.github.io/posts/nodejs_content_length_timeout/</guid><description>As part of my job, Me and my team are responsible for the data pipeline of our division. Our collection layer of all the analytics events is written in typescript with an express server. It is responsible for handling and processing more than 3M requests every minute.
As part of a rewrite of the collection layer, we noticed that we have requests that take more than a minute to progress. Our p99 response time is a lot better: So why do we have requests that take more than a minute to process?</description></item><item><title>How i created my blog in 30 minutes</title><link>https://zigius.github.io/posts/create_hugo_blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 09:03:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://zigius.github.io/posts/create_hugo_blog/</guid><description>Seems like everyone today has a blog, a vlog and a podcast.
This post will give you a hands on explanation on how to create your blog in 5 minutes, and deploy it on Github pages.
Steps Create the repo To keep things simple, we will create a github pages repository. For a more detailed instruction visit this link
First, go to github and create a new repository with your name.</description></item></channel></rss>